<?xml version="1.0"?>
<pattern id="1234">
  <name> Authentication through Shibboleths </name>
  <description score="B"> Shibboleths are challenge response phrases used for
identification in hostile territory.
 </description>
  <metadata id="nout">
    <created>2015-09-01</created>
    <modified>2015-09-09</modified>
    <evaluated>2015-09-06</evaluated>
    <auditors>
      <auditor>Bart Smits</auditor>
    </auditors>
    <authors>
      <author>Geert de Visser</author>
    </authors>
    <tags>
      <tag>authentication</tag>
      <tag>societal</tag>
      <tag>shibboleth</tag>
    </tags>
    <auditors>
      <auditor>Jacobs Brandt </auditor>
    </auditors>
  </metadata>
  <context score="B">
    <description> How to authenticate without relying on technology.
 </description>
    <name> Non-Technical </name>
  </context>
  <problem score="B">
    <requirements score="B">
      <usability id="8">
        <description> The authentication process should not require undue effort to do.
 </description>
        <name> Effortless Authentication </name>
      </usability>
      <functional id="7">
        <description> Entities that repeatedly try to authenticate with incorrect datashould be locked out of the system for some predefined period oftime.
 </description>
        <name> Able to set limited access attempts </name>
      </functional>
      <performance id="6">
        <description> Processing authentication requests must not take forever, and betimely in their duration.
 </description>
        <name> Timely Authentication </name>
      </performance>
      <reliability id="5">
        <description> Authentication must be consistent and that entities with up-to-dateauthentication details should authentication.
 </description>
        <name> Authentication happens </name>
      </reliability>
      <functional id="4">
        <description> The authentication step must be changable and re-enrollmentpossible.
 </description>
        <name> Changeable </name>
      </functional>
      <functional id="3">
        <description> Solutions must consist of an authentication step.
 </description>
        <name> Authentication Mechanism </name>
      </functional>
      <functional id="2">
        <description> A proof is required that will attest to the authenticity of an entity.
 </description>
        <name> Proof of Authenticity </name>
      </functional>
      <functional id="1">
        <description> Solutions must have a means to enroll entities into theauthentication procedure.
 </description>
        <name> Enrollment </name>
      </functional>
    </requirements>
    <description> How to authenticate entities such that assurances can be made oftheir identity.
 </description>
    <name> Authentication </name>
  </problem>
  <solution score="A">
    <models score="A">
      <dynamic modelTy="uml-sequence">
        <model><![CDATA[
subject -> authenticator : Request to be Authenticated.
authenticator -> subject : Request Proof.
subject -> authenticator : Send Proof.
authenticator -> authenticator : Check Proof.
alt subject is authentic
  authenticator -> subject : Success
else subject is a phony
  authenticator -> subject : Reject
end
]]></model>
        <description> The act of authentication requires that the authentication subject go through a CR mechanism.
 </description>
        <name> Authentication </name>
      </dynamic>
      <dynamic modelTy="uml-sequence">
        <model><![CDATA[
subject -> enroller : Request Enrollment.
enroller -> subject : Provide Shibboleth
subject -> enroller : Acknowledge receipt.
loop until success
  enroller -> subject : Request Authentication
  subject -> enroller : Shibboleth
  alt subject is authentic
    enroller -> subject : Success
  else subject is a phony
    enroller -> subject : Reject
  end
]]></model>
        <description> Subject enrolment, requires that the authenticating subject speaks to the enrollment entitiy. This enrolment entity then interacts with the subject until satisfied that the subjects knowns the phrase.
 </description>
        <name> Enrolement </name>
      </dynamic>
      <structure modelTy="uml-component">
        <model><![CDATA[
component Subject
component Authenticator
component Enroller

interface "Enrolement"   as enrol
interface "Authenticate" as auth

Authenticator - auth  : provides
Enroller      - enrol : provides

Subject ..> enrol : requests
Subject ..> auth  : requests
]]></model>
        <description> Within the shibboleth setup there are three main
        components.  The subject requesting access.  The authenticator
        that performs the authenticity check.  An enrolment component
        that enrols a subject into the system.
 </description>
        <name> Example Structure </name>
      </structure>
    </models>
    <properties>
      <property score="A">
        <traits>
          <general svalue="SATISFIED">
            <affects>
              <affect cvalue="HELPS" id="7"> clearly defined process, but confusion over which phrase used..
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="HELPS" id="6"> parties will now the result immediately.
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="HELPS" id="5"> predefined phrases are learned.
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="MAKES" id="3"> very nature the C-R step is the auththenication step.
 </affect>
            </affects>
            <description> The C-R mechanism is the authentication step.
 </description>
            <name> Act of C-R </name>
          </general>
          <general svalue="SATISFIED">
            <affects>
              <affect cvalue="SOMEPOS" id="8"> can be easy to learn.
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="HELPS" id="4"> new phrases to learn
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="SOMEPOS" id="5"> users will be tested, but may forget later
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="HELPS" id="1"> users have to learn the phrases
 </affect>
            </affects>
            <description> The phrases used are only known to those enrolled in the process.
 </description>
            <name> Learning Shibboleths </name>
          </general>
        </traits>
        <description> Shibboleths are a Challenge Response Mechanism. For authentication, people ask for a phrase to be pronounced. If pronounced incorrectly an error is known to be made.
 </description>
        <name> Shibboleths are a C-R Mechanism </name>
      </property>
      <property score="B">
        <traits>
          <general svalue="SATISFIED">
            <affects>
              <affect cvalue="MAKES" id="2"> virtue of knowledge of how to pronounce the phrase.</affect>
              <affect cvalue="HELPS" id="5">phrase and knowledge of how to pronounce is restricted.</affect>

            </affects>
            <description> The Proof comes from how it is pronounced.
 </description>
            <name> Pronunciation is the Proof </name>
          </general>
          <general svalue="WEAKSATIS">
            <affects>
              <affect cvalue="SOMEPOS" id="3"> phrase and knowledge of how to pronounce is restricted.
 </affect>
              <affect cvalue="SOMEPOS" id="2"> restricting choice of phrase.
 </affect>
            </affects>
            <description> Depending on the culture and phrased use, knowledge of how to pronounce the phrase may be more wide spread than originally thought.
 </description>
            <name> Known to a select few </name>
          </general>
        </traits>
        <description> A shibboleth is a phrase whose pronunciation is known only to acertain group.
 </description>
        <name> Known Phrase </name>
      </property>
    </properties>
    <description> Shibboleths are a challenge response mechanism that relies on participants to know a series of phrases whose pronunciation is known to only those accustomed with the phrase. When challenged an entity mustbe able to recite and pronounce the shibboleth correctly.
 </description>
    <name> Shibboleths </name>
  </solution>
  <evidence score="A">
Some well known examples from World War Two are: /Schrijver van Scheveningen/---used by the Dutch Resistance; /Visser van Vlissingen/---another phrase used by Dutch Resistance; and /Lollapalooza/---used by US Soldiers in the Pacific Theatre against the Japanese.
These phrases were chosen due to the difficulty in pronunciation that non-native speakers or had.

    For example, in Dutch the syllable &apos;Sch&apos; has a very distinctive sound that only a fluent/native Dutch speaker will be able to reproduce, and Japanese speakers have difficulty in pronouncing the letter &apos;L&apos;.
Upon encountering a person who claims to be from a certain social group, the person can be challenged to pronounce the group&apos;s shibboleth.
If the person cannot pronounce the shibboleth correctly it can be argued that the person is not an authentic member of the social group, and therefore must be &apos;dealt with&apos;.
 </evidence>
  <studies score="A">
    <study>
      <name>Organising a Party in a Public Space.</name>
      <before>The School of Computer Science are organising a party for Jim at a pub in town. The party is to be held at back of the pub in a enclosed area, policed by security guards. During the party several random strangers come and try to gain access, and fool the security into saying they are ony the list.
      </before>
      <after>
        For the next party organised by the School. They decided to
        use a shibboleth.  During a weekly staff meeting, all memeber
        are told that the pass phrase is: /gif/. A member of staff
        informs the pub&apos;s security team of the pass phrase and
        appropriate pronounciation..  During the party, when random
        strangers (or party goers) attempt to gain access to the
        enclosed area, they are asked for the pass-phrase. Those who
        correctl pronounce the phrases gain access. Those that cannot,
        do not gain access.
      </after>
    </study>
  </studies>
</pattern>
